

eduardocsilva2000@gmail.com

+351 910597715

Porto, Portugal

eduardocsilva.github.io

in

linkedin.com/in/eduardo-csilva

github.com/eduardocsilva

SOFT SKILLS

Communication

Leadership

Teamwork

Flexibility

Proactivity

Independence

Problem Solving

LANGUAGES

Portuguese

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

English

Full Professional Proficiency

INTERESTS

Programming

Technology

Artificial Intelligence

Machine Learning

Web Development

Reading

Music

Sports

Eduardo Silva

Informatics Engineering Student

An independent and self-motivated student finishing a Bachelor's Degree in Informatics Engineering at ISEP (current average grade: 17,8 / 20), with a strong background in Software Engineering and Web Development, as well as Data Science and Machine Learning, aspiring to a professional career in Artificial Intelligence. Strong team spirit and creativity due to 9 years as a federated football player and 4 years of experience as a musician.

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree in Informatics Engineering Instituto Superior de Engenharia do Porto

09/2018 - Present

Course Units

- Software and Application Engineering
 - Data Science and Machine Learning
- Advanced Algorithms and Data Structures
- Linear Algebra and Computational Mathematics

Current Average Grade: 17,8 / 20

Sciences and Technologies - High School

Escola Secundária de Valongo

09/2015 - 07/2018 Final Average Grade: 19 / 20

WORK EXPERIENCE

Machine Learning Engineer (Intern)

E-goi

03/2021 - 07/2021

Matosinhos, Porto, Portugal Achievements/Tasks

Member of Informatics Department

Núcleo de Estudantes de Informática - ISEP

03/2021 - Present Porto, Portugal

Developed a contact list cleaning system, supported by a ML model for e-mail deliverability classification

PROJECTS

Internship Project - Automatic Contact List Cleaning System (E-goi) (03/2021 - 07/2021)

Technologies Used: JavaScript, Angular.js, PHP, Zend, R, Python, Jupyter, FastAPI, Scikit-learn, SQLAlchemy, MySQL, SQLite, etc.

Laboratory and Project 5 - Public Transport Planning and Management App (09/2020 - 01/2021) Technologies Used: Node.js, React/Redux, C#, .NET Core, SQL Server, MongoDB, UML, etc. (Grade: 19 / 20)

Laboratory and Project 4 - Factory Floor Management Application (03/2020 - 07/2020)

Technologies Used: Java, C, JSON, XML, XSD, XSL, H2 SQL, UML (Grade: 19 / 20)

Laboratory and Project 3 - Ride-Sharing Management Application (09/2019 - 01/2020)

Technologies Used: Java, JPA, Oracle SQL, UML (Grade: 19/20)

CERTIFICATES

Machine Learning - Stanford University (Coursera) (60 hours) (08/2020 - 11/2020)

Introduction to Machine Learning (Supervised and Unsupervised Learning), Data Mining and Statistical Pattern Recognition

HARD SKILLS

Languages: Python, R, HTML, CSS, JavaScript/TypeScript, Java, C#, C, C++, Prolog

Frameworks & Libraries: Scikit-Learn, TensorFlow, Spark MLlib, FastAPI, SQLAlchemy, React.js

Databases: MongoDB, SQLite, MySQL, MariaDB, SQL Server, Oracle SQL, H2

Testing: Unit, Integration, API, End 2 End, Machine Learning Specific (e.g. K-Fold Cross Validation)

OTHER SKILLS

Musician (10/2017 - Present)

Guitarist for 3.5 years, Ballroom Dancer for 2 years and Drummer for 2 years

Federated Football Player (08/2008 - 08/2017)

Goalkeeper for the clubs União Desportiva Valonguense (2008-2014) and União Desportiva Sousense (2014-2017)